Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're going outside for our lesson.
我是Catherine，今天我们到户外上课。
That's right.
没错。
Today we are gardening.
今天我们要做园艺。
We are going to set up our own garden.
我们要自己建一个花园。
Okay, that means growing plants and maybe even food.
好的，这意味着种植物，甚至可能种食物。
So let's take a listen to this dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk more about
那么我们先听一段对话，稍后再回来详细讨论
it.
它。
I've decided to grow my own garden.
我决定自己种个花园。
What?
什么？
You don't know the first thing about gardening.
你对园艺一窍不通。
On the contrary, I've been reading a lot of books about the subject.
恰恰相反，我读了很多关于园艺的书。
Oh yeah?
哦，是吗？
Tell me then, smarty pants.
那告诉我吧，聪明鬼。
How will you go about setting up your garden?
你打算怎么建你的花园？
Well, first I need to buy some things such as fertilizer, seeds and tools.
嗯，首先我需要买些东西，比如肥料、种子和工具。
What type of tools?
什么类型的工具？
You know, the basics.
你知道的，基本工具。
A rake, shovel, spade and a hoe.
耙子、铲子、小铲子和锄头。
Right.
对。
Well it seems like you have all your bases covered.
嗯，看来你准备得很周全。
What's next?
接下来呢？
I'll till the soil and then sow the seeds.
我会翻土，然后播种。
I'll then add some fertilizer and voila, gardening all done.
然后加些肥料，瞧，园艺就搞定了。
Well, good luck with your garden, especially considering we're in the dry season and it
嗯，祝你的花园好运，尤其是考虑到现在正值旱季，
won't rain for the next three months.
未来三个月都不会下雨。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So a lot of vocab related to gardening.
所以有很多与园艺相关的词汇。
We mentioned a lot of tools and we're going to explain a lot of those now on Language
我们提到了很多工具，现在在“语言小贴士”环节
Takeaway.
会解释这些词。
Okay, so gardening has some very special tools, like you said, Marco.
好的，园艺有一些非常特殊的工具，就像你说的，Marco。
The first one is one that I am not, well, it's actually not a tool, it's a part of gardening,
第一个是，嗯，其实它不是工具，而是园艺的一部分，
something that we use to help the plants grow and I really don't like it because it smells
我们用来帮助植物生长的东西，我真的很不喜欢它，因为它闻起来
bad.
很臭。
Exactly.
没错。
It smells kind of bad and it has a very strong smell and that is called fertilizer.
它闻起来有点臭，气味很浓，那就是肥料。
Fertilizer.
肥料。
So basically, fertilizer is something that you use in your garden to help the plants
基本上，肥料是你用在花园里帮助植物
grow better.
长得更好的东西。
Right, I think it has a lot of vitamins and minerals that the plant needs to grow better,
对，我认为它含有植物生长所需的大量维生素和矿物质，能让植物长得更好、
faster, stronger.
更快、更强壮。
Exactly, fertilizer.
没错，肥料。
Okay, good.
好的，很好。
Well, now we're going to mention four tools that we use in gardening, basic tools.
嗯，现在我们要提到园艺中使用的四种工具，基本工具。
The first one being a rake.
第一个是耙子。
A rake.
耙子。
Rake.
So a rake is actually something that's very common in most houses, especially houses with
耙子实际上在很多家庭里都很常见，尤其是那些有
a yard or a garden.
院子或花园的房子。
It's not just a gardening tool, but it is something that has a long handle and we use
它不只是园艺工具，而是一种有长柄的东西，我们用它
it to clear the ground of rocks or leaves.
来清理地面上的石头或树叶。
Right, so just imagine it's kind of like a big brush for your garden.
对，所以想象一下，它就像花园里的一把大刷子。
It is.
是的。
It collects things, right?
它能收集东西，对吧？
Right, it's like a big brush that's pulling things out of the ground or away from the
对，它就像一把大刷子，把东西从地面上拉出来或清理掉，
ground, especially in the fall, like October or November when all the leaves fall off.
尤其是在秋天，比如十月或十一月，树叶都落下来的时候。
Like October or November when all the leaves fall off the trees and you have to take them
比如十月或十一月，树叶从树上掉下来，你必须把它们
off the grass, you use a rake to pull them.
从草地上清理掉，你就用耙子把它们耙走。
So you use a rake to pull them and you also call the action of using a rake, you say,
所以用耙子把它们耙走，而使用耙子的动作，你称之为
you rake the garden.
耙地。
To rake, that's right.
耙地，没错。
To rake the leaves.
耙树叶。
I hate raking the leaves.
我讨厌耙树叶。
Alright, and now the other tool that we have is very common, not only in gardening, but
好了，现在我们有的另一个工具很常见，不仅用于园艺，
for construction work, for many things.
还用于建筑工作等很多事情。
You have a shovel.
你有铲子。
Shovel.
铲子。
So a shovel is basically a big metal spoon.
铲子基本上就是一把大金属勺子。
And you use it to make a hole in the ground.
你用它在地上挖洞。
Exactly.
没错。
So, as we say, we use it a lot in gardening to make holes for maybe the plants, but also
所以，正如我们所说，我们在园艺中经常用它来为植物挖洞，但
in construction, if you want to make a hole in the ground, things like this, you use a
在建筑中，如果你想在地上挖洞之类的，也会用
shovel.
铲子。
And now a smaller version of the shovel that you use only with your hand, this is called
现在，铲子的小型版本，只用一只手操作，这叫做
a spade.
小铲子。
A spade.
Now this is very small, like you said, and it's actually special because of its shape.
这个很小，就像你说的，而且它的形状很特别。
A spade has a point.
小铲子有一个尖头。
A shovel is round and a spade has a point.
铲子是圆的，而锹是尖的。
And what's interesting, Marco, is it's actually very common somewhere else.
有趣的是，马可，这在其他地方其实很常见。
In cards.
在纸牌里。
That's right, in cards.
没错，在纸牌里。
So cards have different shapes.
所以纸牌有不同的形状。
One is a heart, one is a diamond.
一个是红心，一个是方块。
One of them is a spade.
其中一个是黑桃。
So the one that's pointy, that's called a spade, and it's used for digging kind of precision
那个尖的，就叫黑桃，它用来挖比较精确的
holes.
洞。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
So you don't want to use a big shovel if you want to make maybe a small hole in the ground,
所以如果你只想在地上挖个小洞，就不想用大铲子，
you would use a spade.
你会用锹。
And now our last tool has kind of a funny spelling.
现在我们最后一个工具拼写有点搞笑。
It's H-O-E, and it's pronounced hoe.
是H-O-E，读作hoe。
Hoe.
锄头。
So again, this is a tool with a very long handle, and you use it to maybe make the ground
再说一次，这是一个长柄工具，用来让地面
softer or to turn up the ground.
变软或者翻土。
So when you're first starting to plant a garden, the ground is very hard, very tough, right?
所以当你刚开始种花园时，地面很硬，很结实，对吧？
And this is a really important tool for that period because you can basically turn up the
这个工具在那个阶段非常重要，因为你可以翻动
ground.
土壤。
You're not digging anything, but you're mixing up the dirt a little bit to make it softer.
你不是在挖东西，而是稍微混合一下泥土，让它变软。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So that's when you use this tool.
所以这就是用这个工具的时候。
It's kind of a dirt or a soil mixer.
它有点像泥土或土壤搅拌器。
You can also pull out those nasty weeds with a hoe.
你也可以用锄头拔掉那些讨厌的杂草。
Okay, good.
好的，不错。
So four key tools that we've just taken a look at now.
现在我们刚看了四种关键工具。
But now let's move on to two verbs that are basically very important when you're talking
但现在我们来看两个动词，在谈论
about gardening and all this.
园艺之类的时候，它们非常重要。
As you mentioned, you talked about mixing the soil.
你刚才提到了混合土壤。
And in the next line, we see that it says, I'll till the soil.
在下一行，我们看到它说，我会翻耕土壤。
To till.
翻耕。
Okay, so basically this is a way of turning up that soil, but you're doing it kind of
好的，这基本上是一种翻土的方式，但你是成行地
in lines, right?
做，对吧？
So you're mixing up the soil and making it soft.
所以你混合土壤，让它变软。
You're preparing the soil for planting.
你在为种植准备土壤。
And so you till the soil.
所以你翻耕土壤。
Soil of course, in this case, is that dirt.
这里的土壤当然就是那种泥土。
It's earth.
是土地。
Right, it's earth.
对，是土地。
So to till is to prepare it for planting.
所以翻耕就是为种植做准备。
Till the soil, that's right.
翻耕土壤，没错。
To till the soil, okay.
翻耕土壤，好的。
And what do we do after the soil has been tilled?
土壤翻耕后我们做什么？
Well then we sow the seeds.
然后我们播种。
Okay, so seeds are baby plants basically.
好的，种子基本上就是幼苗。
And we sow the seeds.
我们播种。
When we sow the seeds, we're putting the seeds into the ground.
当我们播种时，我们把种子放进地里。
So that's basically planting the seeds.
所以这基本上就是种植种子。
You can say we plant the seeds or we sow the seeds.
你可以说我们种种子或我们播种。
And the opposite of sowing?
播种的反义词是什么？
The opposite of sowing is reaping.
播种的反义词是收获。
R-E-A-P, to reap.
R-E-A-P，收获。
So we actually have a phrase in English.
所以英语里有一个短语。
This is very, very famous, very common.
这个非常非常有名，非常常见。
We say, you reap what you sow.
我们说，种瓜得瓜，种豆得豆。
You reap what you sow, that's right.
种瓜得瓜，种豆得豆，没错。
So you basically collect what you planted and that's kind of what you do in life.
所以你基本上收获你种下的东西，这在生活中也是如此。
So we say if you haven't planted anything good, you're not going to reap anything good.
所以我们说如果你没种下好东西，你就不会收获好东西。
Exactly.
没错。
It's a very popular phrase.
这是一个很流行的短语。
All right, so we've covered a lot of vocab here.
好了，我们这里讲了很多词汇。
Why don't we go back, listen to the dialogue again, and we'll be back with Fluency Builder.
我们为什么不回去再听一遍对话，然后回来做流利度练习。
I've decided to grow my own garden.
我决定自己种个花园。
What?
什么？
You don't know the first thing about gardening.
你对园艺一窍不通。
On the contrary, I've been reading a lot of books about the subject.
恰恰相反，我读了很多关于这个主题的书。
Oh yeah?
哦，是吗？
Tell me then, smarty pants.
那告诉我吧，聪明鬼。
How will you go about setting up your garden?
你打算怎么开始弄你的花园？
Well, first I need to buy some things such as fertilizer, seeds, and tools.
嗯，首先我需要买些东西，比如肥料、种子和工具。
What type of tools?
什么类型的工具？
You know, the basics.
你知道的，基本工具。
A rake, shovel, spade, and a hoe.
耙子、铲子、锹和锄头。
Right.
对。
Well, it seems like you have all your bases covered.
嗯，看来你考虑得很周全。
What's next?
下一步是什么？
I'll till the soil and then sow the seeds.
我会翻耕土壤，然后播种。
I'll then add some fertilizer and voila, gardening all done.
然后加些肥料，瞧，园艺就搞定了。
Well, good luck with your garden, especially considering we're in the dry season and it
嗯，祝你的花园好运，特别是考虑到我们现在是旱季，而且
won't rain for the next three months.
未来三个月不会下雨。
All right, we're back and we have four phrases for you on Fluency Builder and we're going
好了，我们回来了，在流利度构建器中有四个短语要讲，我们接下来
to take a look at those now.
就来看看这些短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
This first phrase is useful in any conversation, I think, especially if you're trying to impress
第一个短语在任何对话中都很实用，我觉得，尤其是你想给某人留下好印象时。
somebody.
某人。
So basically, one person in this dialogue says, you know what, you don't know the first
基本上，这段对话中一个人说，你知道吗，你对园艺一窍不通。
thing about gardening.
一窍不通。
That means you don't know anything about gardening.
意思是你对园艺一无所知。
And what does he say in response?
那他怎么回应呢？
On the contrary.
恰恰相反。
So the contrary means the opposite.
所以“contrary”意思是相反。
So basically this means the opposite is true.
所以基本上就是说事实正好相反。
Right.
对。
You're basically saying, I disagree.
你基本上是在说，我不同意。
What you are saying is false.
你说的是错的。
It's actually the opposite.
实际上正好相反。
So maybe I have a feeling, Marco, that it's going to rain tomorrow.
所以，马可，我可能觉得明天会下雨。
Actually, on the contrary, I saw in the news that it's going to be very sunny tomorrow.
实际上，恰恰相反，我在新闻里看到明天会是大晴天。
Oh, well, that's good news.
哦，那倒是好消息。
So that's a way of maybe politely disagreeing with someone or saying to someone that, well,
所以这是一种礼貌地表示不同意或告诉某人，嗯，
you're wrong.
你错了的方式。
It's actually the opposite of what you're saying.
实际上和你说的正好相反。
Okay.
好的。
Moving on to our second phrase, it's actually a colloquial way of kind of making fun of
接着看第二个短语，这是一种口语化的方式，用来调侃
someone when you say, all right, then, smarty pants.
某人，当你说，好吧，聪明裤。
Okay, smarty pants.
好的，聪明裤。
Don't think about this too much.
别想太多。
We're not talking about pants, actually.
我们说的不是裤子。
But this is a way of saying, okay, if you're so smart, then tell me that.
但这是种说法，意思是，好吧，如果你这么聪明，那告诉我吧。
It's sarcasm.
这是讽刺。
Exactly.
没错。
So this person says, oh, actually, I know a lot about gardening.
所以这个人说，哦，实际上我对园艺很了解。
And the other person says, oh, really, smarty pants.
另一个人就说，哦，真的吗，聪明裤。
So you can actually describe a person in this way.
所以你可以这样形容一个人。
Maybe a person that thinks they know a lot or sometimes what you say, a Mr. Know-it-all.
也许是一个自认为懂得很多的人，或者有时你说的“万事通先生”。
You also say, it's a smarty pants.
你也可以说，他是个聪明裤。
Right.
对。
A person that thinks they know a lot or everything even.
一个自认为懂得很多甚至一切的人。
Right.
对。
Mr. Know-it-all or a smarty pants.
万事通先生或聪明裤。
All right.
好的。
And our third phrase is interesting because we have a setup here.
第三个短语很有趣，因为我们这里有个设定。
When the person says, how will you go about setting up your garden?
当这个人说，你打算怎么着手布置你的花园？
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So to go about doing something.
所以“to go about doing something”。
There's two important parts of this.
这有两个重要部分。
So Marco, the first part is how you go about.
所以马可，第一部分是“how you go about”。
This means how you do.
意思是“你怎么做”。
Right.
对。
So you can say, how will you do this?
所以你可以说，你会怎么做？
What's your approach?
你的方法是什么？
So how will you go about plus and then the verb in ing.
所以“how will you go about”加上动词的ing形式。
So how will you go about setting up your garden?
所以“how will you go about setting up your garden？”
How will you start or what is your approach to creating your garden?
你怎么开始，或者你创建花园的方法是什么？
So maybe Marco, you want to write a book and I can ask you, well, how will you go about
所以也许马可，你想写一本书，我可以问你，嗯，你打算怎么着手
starting your book?
开始写你的书？
Right.
对。
Or if I'm writing a book, you can say, how will you go about investigating for your book?
或者如果我在写书，你可以说，你打算怎么着手为你的书做调研？
So what is the approach you're going to take?
所以你要采取什么方法？
How will you do it?
你会怎么做？
How do you plan on, how do you plan on doing something?
你打算怎么做某事？
Exactly.
没错。
And our final phrase here is a very commonly used for all sorts of situations.
最后一个短语在各种情况下都非常常用。
Basically if a person is prepared, you say, well, you have all your bases covered.
基本上，如果一个人准备充分，你会说，嗯，你面面俱到了。
Okay.
好的。
This is a great phrase.
这是个很棒的短语。
It comes right from sports.
它来自体育。
Very common in English to have sports phrases.
英语中体育短语很常见。
This comes from the sport baseball.
这个来自棒球运动。
Right.
对。
So in baseball, the field is a diamond.
在棒球中，场地是菱形。
There are four corners or four bases and the runners have to go from one base to the other
有四个角或四个垒，跑垒员必须从一个垒到另一个垒，
one, two, three, four, and then they get a point.
一、二、三、四，然后得分。
But in this case we're saying the other team, they have their bases covered.
但这里我们说的是对方球队，他们守住了垒。
That means they're protecting their bases.
意思是他们在保护自己的垒。
And in speech we say, if you have your bases covered, like you said, Marco, you're very
在口语中我们说，如果你已经面面俱到，就像你说的，Marco，你非常
well prepared.
准备充分。
Right.
对。
So you're, you're ready, you're prepared.
所以你已经准备好了，你准备妥当了。
You have really planned out and thought of what you're going to do.
你真的计划好了，想好了要做什么。
So you have all your bases covered.
所以你已经面面俱到了。
So Marco, for example, you just told me that it's going to be sunny tomorrow, but I think
所以Marco，比如，你刚才告诉我明天会是晴天，但我认为
it still might rain.
可能还是会下雨。
So to have all my bases covered, I'm going to bring an umbrella anyway.
所以为了面面俱到，我还是会带把伞。
Just in case.
以防万一。
Or maybe you have a presentation at work and you've prepared your PowerPoint presentation.
或者也许你在工作上有演示，你准备好了你的PowerPoint演示文稿。
You have your, your drawings, your copies, you have everything ready.
你有了图纸、复印件，一切都准备好了。
You have all your bases covered for that meeting.
你已经为那次会议面面俱到了。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So why don't we go back and listen to our dialogue for the last time and we'll be back
那我们最后再听一遍对话，然后回来再聊一会儿。
to talk a little bit more.
再聊一会儿。
I've decided to grow my own garden.
我决定自己种个花园。
What?
什么？
You don't know the first thing about gardening.
你对园艺一窍不通。
On the contrary, I've been reading a lot of books about the subject.
恰恰相反，我读了很多关于这方面的书。
Oh yeah?
哦，是吗？
Tell me then, smarty pants.
那告诉我吧，聪明鬼。
How will you go about setting up your garden?
你打算怎么布置你的花园？
Well, first I need to buy some things such as fertilizer, seeds and tools.
嗯，首先我需要买些东西，比如肥料、种子和工具。
What type of tools?
什么类型的工具？
You know, the basics.
你知道的，基本工具。
A rake, shovel, spade and a hoe.
耙子、铲子、铁锹和锄头。
Right.
对。
Well it seems like you have all your bases covered.
嗯，看来你已经面面俱到了。
What's next?
接下来呢？
I'll till the soil and then sow the seeds.
我会翻土，然后播种。
I'll then add some fertilizer and voila, gardening all done.
然后加些肥料，瞧，园艺就完成了。
Well good luck with your garden, especially considering we're in the dry season and it
嗯，祝你的花园好运，尤其是考虑到我们现在是旱季，接下来三个月
won't rain for the next three months.
都不会下雨。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So gardening is actually a very popular thing in many countries.
园艺在很多国家其实很流行。
I know many people as well who prefer to have their own personal garden to grow their own
我也认识很多人，他们更喜欢有自己的私人花园来种自己的
vegetables which they say taste a lot different from the ones you buy at the supermarket.
蔬菜，他们说这些蔬菜的味道和超市买的大不相同。
They do.
确实如此。
I think personally that home grown vegetables, so vegetables that you grow yourself, tend
我个人认为，自家种的蔬菜，也就是你自己种的蔬菜，往往
to taste a lot better than the ones you get in the grocery store.
比在杂货店买的要好吃得多。
They also look different.
它们看起来也不一样。
They're not as pretty, but that's because they have less chemicals.
它们没那么漂亮，但那是因为它们含的化学物质更少。
I think it's a very popular thing and well not only gardening your own vegetables but
我觉得这很流行，而且不仅仅是种自己的蔬菜，
some people just enjoy it as a hobby to have some plants and different types of things
有些人只是把它当作一种爱好，在后院种些植物和不同种类的东西。
in their backyard.
在后院种些植物和不同种类的东西。
Yeah, many people say it's very relaxing.
是啊，很多人说这很放松。
You get to go outside, you're in the sunshine, it's a very calming activity.
你可以到户外，晒晒太阳，这是一种很平静的活动。
It seems like it's very relaxing.
看起来确实很放松。
A little bit boring at times.
有时候有点无聊。
Basically you're waiting for your plants to grow, but I imagine that once they do, you've
基本上你就是在等植物长大，但我想一旦它们长大了，你
accomplished it, it must be great to see that you've actually brought life.
就完成了，看到自己真的创造了生命，一定很棒。
I'm sure.
我肯定。
Like 20 minutes every day is not so bad.
比如每天20分钟，也不算太糟。
Yeah.
是啊。
It's actually a very interesting hobby and we want to know if in your country, in your
这其实是一个很有趣的爱好，我们想知道在你的国家，你的
town, do you have enough space for a garden?
城镇，你有足够的空间建花园吗？
Do you like gardening or maybe growing your own food?
你喜欢园艺或者自己种食物吗？
I think that's a very interesting topic.
我觉得这是个很有趣的话题。
Yeah, let us know what you think.
是啊，告诉我们你的想法。
Do you do this?
你这样做吗？
Yeah, I do.
是的，我这样做。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you there.
希望在那里见到你。
All right.
好的。
Bye.
再见。
Have a nice time.
祝你愉快。